My name is Paul Anderson.
I'm the director and I'm here
with the fabulous Milla Jovovich.
Hi, I'm Milla Jovovich
and I'm one of the actors in this movie.
And I'm sitting next to
the fabulous Michelle Rodriguez.
You sounded like a drag
when you were introducing me.
And I'm sitting next to Jeremy Bolt.
And I'm one of the many
producers on this film.
- And one of the many actors in the movie.
- Yeah.
He's actually in more scenes
than either Michelle or I.
Yeah.
Yes, there should be
a competition of who can spot me.
I'm in the film three times.
Hey, hey. Listen to this stuff, it's important.
Okay.
- This is the voice of Jason Isaacs.
- Unpaid.
Unpaid and uncredited.
No, no, actually, I did pay him.
- Did you?
- I just didn't credit him.
- Did we pay him?
- How much did you pay him?
Yeah, he said, "Don't you think I should
get something for this?"
Because you pulled him back in
to do the voiceover for this so many times.
It wasn't your fault
because you couldn't do it.
We had to rely on our line producer,
Chris Symes, and he wasn't very good at it.
Well, he's going to
enjoy listening to the DVD.
Yeah, I know, but he's very,
very good at other things.
This is important because I remember
when this shot occurred to Paul,
first day of shooting, I think.
He was talking to Richard Yuricich,
the visual effects supervisor...
That's not what they
really wanna know about.
No, you remember this.
This was a great moment.
He had the idea with Richard to start
like it was a pin prick
of light at the end of a big tunnel
and then just to put black all around it
and then slowly be pulled
into the world of Resident Evil.
Which I think is one of the coolest
openings that we've done, actually.
Yeah, I think it's pretty awesome.
I think it sucks.
Honestly, I think it would
have been much better...
- That's 'cause you... If you'd been in it...
- Yeah, exactly.
You should have been there. But,
you know what? You could have been there.
We don't know that's not you in that suit.
Okay, that is Milla Jovovich,
ladies and gentlemen.
Jovovich!
Jovovich! How difficult is it,
for God's sakes?
We made a movie together.
Jesus Christ.
If she doesn't know my last name,
I have no hope.
- No hope.
- Come on, stop it.
- Unbelievable.
- Hey, that right there is the anti-virus.
By the way.
Have you guys seen
that really great commercial?
Look at that box, isn't that amazing?
- That box drove me insane.
- The one that starts off,
"The Umbrella Corporation.
Do you wanna live forever?
"Stay young?
The Umbrella Corporation can help you."
That box, by the way, Paul drove me mad.
He kept sending it back and back and back.
What happened to that commercial?
Yeah, I wanna know that, too.
It's out there. The Umbrella Corporation
commercial, it's out there.
- Oh, that's good. That's good.
- I haven't seen it.
- It's got a Blair Witch touch.
- And I can say, excuse me,
- Sunday night.
- Is it real?
Sunday before our opening,
didn't see one trailer.
- No, you were watching...
- Can I just be negative for a second?
Yeah, they deliberately didn't buy on Fox
because you can't put
an R-rated trailer on The Simpsons
and only old people watch X Files.
I saw our trailer on The Simpsons,
on King of the Hill,
- and Malcolm in the Middle.
- No.
- Screw censorship.
- Paul, come on, back me up on this.
Because, like, I'm not crazy.
I don't watch TV. I watch The Simpsons,
I watch King of the Hill.
Okay, I saw our trailer on King of the Hill.
But we don't want
you to come see the movie.
- Look at the dogs.
- Great.
- So we're not advertising to you.
- Exactly.
These dogs are fantastic.
If you guys missed it,
there was a virus dropped
and we saw it kind of
go into the ventilation system.
I think if they buy this,
they've seen the movie.
- They may have watched the movie.
- Oh.
It's the DVD.
May have. I don't know, but when I saw
Freddie Got Fingered,
I totally went for the commentary first.
Oh my God, we were watching
Life of Brian on DVD the other night,
and of course,
where's the first place that Paul goes to?
Colour bar.
Colour bar, which is like, test pattern.
On the DVD, and of course
it's the first thing we wanted to see.
We were like, "Oh, what's a colour bar?"
They look like ICM agents in there.
- He looks like such an ICM agent.
- He looks like my old agent.
Oh.
Once you see a bunch of people
on a computer screen,
you just know they're screwed.
It's automatic.
It's like, "We know these people
are screwed, they're being watched.
"They're screwed. That's it."
Oh, I love to see
people get screwed onscreen.
It's so great.
I wish we could just save it all
for the screen and not for real life.
Hello?
What's happening?
Line's dead.
- What's the problem?
- The doors won't open.
What about the ones at the back?
Locked as well.
There's no fire here. No fire.
- The code doesn't work!
- No fire!
- What's wrong with you?
- The door won't open!
And this water isn't going anywhere.
- What?
- It's a sealed room.
- Help me with the door!
- Oh, fuck the doors!
We have to get out of here.
What's going on?
Has this happened before?
We have to get out of here.
If you guys make this movie a huge hit
and this DVD has huge sales,
- I'll get breast enhancement surgery.
- Milla will get butt implants.
Milla Jovovich will get
butt implants for part two.
Jovovich! Jovovich!
What's your problem?
Jovovich. There you go.
- Yeah.
- Oh, look at that. That's sick.
That is, like, my nightmare.
To be dropped like that.
- So sick.
- So awesome.
I think if you jump when it hits
the bottom, nothing will happen to you.
- Urban myth.
- Doesn't work.
Urban myth, I tried it.
- Yeah, you tried it?
- This happens to me all the time, you know.
How the hell do you guys know? Liars.
I was in an elevator that crashed.
That's where the idea
for this scene comes from.
- You can't jump?
- No, it doesn't work.
Paul had an elevator accident
when he was a young boy.
It traumatised him.
He now won't take elevators, only stairs.
And he'll do elevator scenes
in every movie he makes.
Yeah.
For the rest of his life.
Oh, this is good.
That's suspense right there, man.
So, are we just gonna do
commentary on the whole movie?
- Yeah.
- This is fun. Serious?
- So, watch this, this is...
- Oh my God, is that what we're doing?
So, we're watching
the whole movie right now?
- Yes.
- Oh, awesome!
This is great.
Everybody's dying. I love it.
This is the halon scene.
She looks like... No, this is great.
What I loved what Paul did with this scene
is that he made her
like a fish on dry land, gasping.
And you just see her quivering.
- It's totally cool.
- I love it.
- That sucks. You go to work, you die.
- Don't do it, don't do it.
Listen, it's over for you guys,
let's just fast forward.
- Let's get to my bits.
- That sucks, man.
Imagine, you would have called in sick,
none of this would have happened to you.
Oh, God.
Yep, that's what they're all thinking.
"I should have called in sick."
What's going on in our world today?
"We're all gonna die down here."
I really like that.
Oh, God.
So, this elevator scene,
the elevator is on a hydraulic rig,
so it only goes up or down
about six or seven feet.
And it's all perfectly safe, as well.
Although, when we were shooting it,
it just looked terrifying. Because...
Yeah, I cannot imagine
having that much trust in people.
I wanted to see her head get chopped off.
Well, because the elevator
can't go any lower than the floor,
I mean, it actually rests on the floor,
so there's no danger
to her when it was going down.
And when it goes up, as well,
there was huge metal bars,
so there's no way the elevator could
have actually decapitated her for real.
That floor was all just light wood.
You can actually see the floor bending.
If you look at this shot here, you can see
that the floor was actually bending
because it was a breakaway floor,
just in case Indra, who's the actress,
her head snapped forward,
the floor was just made out
of very lightweight plastic.
See, I wanted to see that.
What happened, Paul?
It's rated R. Gore, hello? Why didn't we
see her head get chopped off and blood?
Listen, if we had one more drop of blood,
we wouldn't even be rated R.
Yeah, we would have been NC-17.
I think Milla's naked here.
I sure am.
What are you doing
without your clothes, you ho?
You know me, I just love to do those
gratuitous nudity scenes.
Love it. In every contract I have.
That's not what your agent said.
Yeah.
I remember that bit of the negotiation.
But somehow or other, you got it in there.
Hey, wasn't there
controversy about the gas here?
At first?
Well, I did pass gas in this scene.
Not your farts, Milla,
we're talking about the gas
that comes out of the bathroom thingamajig.
Oh, we're usually talking about my farts,
so I just took it for granted.
So, this is the scene...
Okay, listen, can I do my commentary now?
- Oh, yeah.
- This is me.
This is me, like you know, waking up,
and like, remembering stuff.
Oh, scar. Sexy.
- And now here comes flashback.
- I'm kind of cute.
And these flashbacks
were computer-graded,
they were all digitally graded,
which is why the colours are so great.
And we went in and we took each
individual frame of the shot
and bits of the shot
and coloured them separately.
So, for example, in the flashbacks,
they're very desaturated.
We took a lot of colour out.
Okay, can I just say, who cares about that?
You just saw my nipple.
It's a very, very good shot, though.
I mean, no one cares about the grading.
What about the gas?
All I have to say is, like,
how committed am I to this picture?
- That was like full nipple shot.
- Where did you see the gas?
It's transparent.
If you were really committed,
we'd have seen both nipples.
Oh yeah, whatever.
Listen, we have to have
some class in this movie.
You know, it adds
a little bit of class, I mean, honestly.
We have to hold
something back for the sequel.
- Commitment is showing both nipples.
- Apparently we've got breast enhancement.
- And butt enhancement.
- He said "breast."
So, what's up? What's the deal?
Why is she by herself in a mansion?
We don't know, Michelle.
That's the whole fucking point,
Jesus Christ.
Later on in the movie when you watch
James Purefoy write that note,
you'll notice a terrible continuity.
That the handwriting doesn't match at all.
- Really? It looked the same to me.
- Yeah.
You see it so far into the movie
you just never notice.
Well, now they'll know, then.
Well, now hopefully they've paid
to see the movie a couple of times.
- What gun is that, Paul?
- Those are cool guns.
- That is an MP5, is it not, Michelle?
- Yes it is.
Michelle's favourite gun,
her weapon of choice.
My luscious machine gun.
Although Milla got the really cool gun.
The one that shoots actual missiles.
I know, but we couldn't
use it, really, in the end.
You didn't get to use it, did you?
Well, I did on the first ending,
but then we cut that out.
That sucks.
- I do like the ending, Paul, by the way.
- The new one?
- It's freaking sick.
- Yeah, I'm really glad we shot it.
The whole scene, the way you pulled back.
The chaos.
Now, just where we shot, this mansion
is actually an old Nazi barracks.
Yeah.
Fuck, it was so creepy.
It was so creepy. During WWII,
one of Hitler's top regiments
was posted there.
And then after the war
the Russians were there.
So, there was this fireplace
and above one fire
was this hammer and sickle,
and then there was this other fireplace
and above it was a swastika.
And it's all painted over
because they tried to cover it up.
So, there was a lot of ghosts in this place.
I never went to the bathroom by myself.
It was very, very creepy.
I mean, the crew couldn't wait
to get out of there.
You could go inside the walls of this place.
Michelle went with
all the kids up in to the attic...
- I had a kid with me, I wasn't by myself.
- She could not talk me into doing that.
Did you go upstairs
and see the padded cells?
No. They had padded cells? Sick.
They had padded cells with these one way
mirrors that you could look through
where they actually
carried out interrogations.
There were so many strange ghosts.
They shot a little bit
of Enemy at the Gates around here.
Well, I hope we have
better box office than that.
Yeah. I hope it wasn't where those signs
were that says "Beware of mines."
For Christ's sake. You're walking around
the set and it says beware of freaking mines.
I didn't see that.
I totally did.
You didn't see the Nazi temple, either?
It was sick.
This set was sick.
In case you haven't gathered it,
the whole movie, or nearly all of the movie,
was shot in Germany, mainly in Berlin.
Which was a fantastic city to shoot in.
Computer-generated crows, right there.
- Those were all computer generated?
- Yep.
Oh, God. In Germany there's so many crows,
I thought you guys actually captured them.
Go figure.
- That I like. That's Resident Evil right there.
- You like that?
Where you hear the sound of the leaves.
It's all about that quiet subtleness.
And talking of quiet subtleness,
here comes Marilyn Manson.
That's Eric Mabius.
No, no. The soundtrack's Marilyn Manson.
Oh, well that's Middle America, man.
We've gotta satisfy them.
It's all about the charts, baby.
It's all good.
Why do I have a feeling that our songs
are never gonna get on the charts?
I mean, hello, Slipknot?
You can't get any more kind of left field.
Uh oh. Milla, be nice.
Listen, I can't get
the song out of my head, personally.
Hey, wait, wait. Here comes a line.
Oh, this is great.
That was Martin pretending to be Colin.
Do you remember?
That wasn't actually Colin, that was Martin,
because he was so good, Martin.
- Martin's the man.
- He was really nimble in his uniform.
Seeing as that he's like half the size
of Colin,
I can't believe you made that shot work.
- He got that off.
- Yeah.
Magic of filmmaking.
What are you doing with us?
What about the cop?
Matthew Addison. I'm not getting a match.
Who are you?
I just transferred. They probably
don't even have me on file yet.
The locals are inefficient. It's possible.
Should I secure him here?
No. We take him with us.
You can't do this!
Blow me.
Prep for entry to the Hive.
Literally, Bernie, it was his birthday,
and he came on set at about,
I don't know, 2:30 a.m.,
because we shot all night
during this last... Well, not here,
but inside the mansion when everybody's
breaking through the windows.
Literally 3:00 a.m. comes around,
Bernie comes in with probably 25 bottles
of rosé Taittinger Champagne.
I had a lot of those.
And literally, everyone's like,
"Oh, no, Paul, we'll just have a glass."
But we kept pouring
each other's glasses into our glasses
and all of people's half-empty glasses
we would pour into our glasses.
By the end of the night we were so out of it,
and so drunk,
and poor Paul is freaking because
we have to finish and it's our last day
and he's got like one take
for people crashing into windows
and we're completely
drunk of four butts, like,
"It's okay, no problem."
Well, there are certain traditions
in Germany, like you eat beer...
- You eat sausage and beer...
- You eat beer. You eat beer.
For, like, your second week of shooting.
Really, Jeremy? That's very interesting.
Listen, in Germany, any excuse
to eat beer, they're there.
It's all about chewing the bottle, guys.
It's very good beer in Germany, though.
- Yeah.
- Very, very good beer.
I told my agent two years ago
that if anybody made a script
on Resident Evil I wanna be a part of it
and then she got me
a nice interview with Paul.
And once I sat down with him, God,
like he had all the details
of the video game...
And I thought he was gonna be
some dickhead director
trying to make an extra buck,
not knowing jack about the video game.
Paul is honestly the only director in history
that it was his dream
to make Resident Evil the movie.
Usually you have directors wanting
to make their twisted life stories.
Or just these really artistic films
about what happened to them
as children that was dysfunctional.
This happened to me as a child.
What are you talking about?
This is my art movie.
Are you saying this is not an art movie?
Paul's not only a director,
I think he's also the overgrown kid
that sits there and plays these games.
A geek.
So, he knew about codes that I had no clue,
you know what I mean?
And that's pretty sick.
Because I waste away my life with video
games when I can get a chance, you know?
But that was a nice thing about this movie,
was that everyone involved in it
was really into the video game.
You know, Michelle had played it,
Milla had played it,
and I made a lot of the crew either
play the game or watch tapes of the game
so that they understood
what Resident Evil was all about.
So, for example, this train is based
on the train from Resident Evil 2,
so if you're a fan of the game,
there's a hell of a lot of production design
in the movie
that's taken directly from the game.
Look at this, I mean it's totally...
This is Michelle's hottest shot.
He should have totally kept that
Umbrella Corporation logo,
and he did and I'm so happy about that.
It's those little details that people
get pissed off when they don't see.
You know what I mean?
That's why they don't...
Like X-Men, I had to watch it
three times to really get into it
because of the simple fact
that the costumes weren't...
I'm sure they were happy about that.
I hope there's a lot of people like Michelle
that need to see our movie three times.
But the third time I was finally into it.
By the third time she was like,
"No, this sucks."
No, no, by the third time I was totally into it.
It was totally cool.
Watch this light. Follow it.
It's just sick. You're in there.
Like, you're in there. You're feeling it.
It's so quiet and subtle,
and, like, the mansions,
and just the whole fact
that she's so vulnerable.
You know, the main character
in the video game is so...
In a tube top and a miniskirt.
It's realistic because
all she's got is a freaking knife.
She's gotta go look for the gun.
You run out of ammo, you don't get 20 lives,
you know what I mean?
Well, actually you do,
but you know what I mean?
- Only if you cheat.
- You have to start from the beginning again.
Well, if you get a memory card.
That too, but I just like
the quiet subtlety of it.
The video game, it's just sick,
the way that you just walk around
and you don't know
what the hell's around the corner.
That's the beauty of it.
And the fact that somebody
could be at the controls
and you could just tell them what to do.
Which I love, because I'm not a big
sitting behind the controller...
But you like telling people what to do.
But I love telling my little brother, "Okay,
go here, turn the corner, look in there."
And Milla Jovovich's next debut
will be as a director, ladies and gentlemen.
As you can tell right now,
she's a control freak.
The sequel.
But you know what
I love about this game, too?
I play some sick games with my brother.
He's 13 years old.
- This kid...
- I thought you were gonna say "with Paul."
That too.
First of all, he's a straight A student,
but this kid plays
let's say a game like Half-Life,
I don't know if you've ever played that,
but literally, this game, it's like your POV
and you have crowbars
and machine guns and whatnot,
and literally, people that you're
supposed to rescue, you can kill them.
And the game lets you actually
hunt them down and kill them.
And they're running away from you, going
"What are you doing? You can't kill me."
And you follow them and you kill them,
and sometimes you kill them with a crowbar
just smashing them over the head
and they're screaming and it's horrendous.
And it's fun, I mean it's fun for me,
it's fun for people that know better,
but for kids like 13 years old
like my brother,
it made me a little bit nervous.
So, I love Resident Evil, too, because
the fact that you're killing zombies.
You know, you're not going into
a shopping mall and spraying people down.
Come on, you're totally
down with Grand Theft Auto.
It's for adults. It's not for kids.
No, I love Grand Theft Auto,
but exactly, it's for adults.
I mean I love to be psychotic and...
We don't have to advertise
Grand Theft Auto.
Resident Evil.
Resident Evil is super cool
because it still is hard core
without killing people in recognisable
scenes, which I kind of liked.
I mean, if I'm gonna play something with
my brother, I'd rather play Resident Evil.
- This is good music as well.
- Grand Theft Auto is for me and my friends.
Yeah, this music...
How cool is this shot?
This is one of your coolest.
Yeah.
Richard did this?
- No.
- Who did this?
Well, not by himself.
Richard Yuricich,
our visual effects supervisor,
who will be having
his own commentary on this DVD
where he'll tell you in much greater detail
how he created that shot.
Yeah, man.
I love power tools.
And they love you.
The Hive has its own defence mechanisms,
all computer-controlled.
A nerve gas was released into the house.
Primary effect of the gas,
complete unconsciousness...
I like toys. I like to play with toys.
I like guns, I like things that affect
other things from far away.
It's fun.
And it's more physical.
I just like it, I think if it's not an incredibly
dramatic thing that I'm doing,
then it has to be extremely physical.
So, it's either one or the other with me.
I think I'm built for movies like this.
I'm believable in parts like this.
And my little brother thinks I'm God now.
So, you know, that was
the main motivation to do this movie.
And again, like I was saying,
I really think the game is super cool
without sort of making kids...
Giving kids this idea that they can
just do things that are just crazy.
I mean, Resident Evil's
a fantasy world, which I love.
I love fantasy games.
Not that far from fantasy, from reality.
Yeah, but you know, you're still,
you're killing zombies, I love that.
I hate to watch my brother act like a psycho,
killing real people in a video game.
Well, not real people,
but what looks like real people.
Halon content has dissipated.
This design, who designed all this stuff?
This is sick.
Well, the mirror, that's Richard Bridgland,
our production designer.
That was beautiful, man.
All the sets, I think,
are really well done, dude.
For the pennies you guys had to work with,
you guys kicked butt.
We had very little money.
That's what I'm saying.
I think you guys are gods for that.
Amazed the hell out of me.
When Richard explained to me
how much little things cost,
I was just like, "No way."
Hollywood is sick.
Well, one of the advantages
we had for the movie was,
because we were shooting in Berlin,
where they have a fantastic, basically an
underground labyrinth beneath the city,
which is where they're
rebuilding the U-Bahn system,
which is their underground transit system,
and we had access to that.
So we had all these
underground train stations and tunnels
and, like this great stairway,
these were all real locations.
And because we used locations,
we saved a lot of money
rather than having to build everything.
And also it gives the movie,
I think, a feeling of reality,
which I think for horror is very important.
I think the more realistic you can be,
the more scary it is.
Oh, hell yeah, man.
This isn't a zombie movie, dude.
This has lots of zombies in it,
but I think this is more about
biohazardous scientific experimentation.
You know, metamorphosis,
and just the whole fact that experimenting
with genealogy and DNA testing
can be very, very, very dangerous.
I don't know,
that's just my personal opinion.
Yeah, this...
I've seen a couple of zombie movies,
and this is not...
It's all about... Like you're in your house...
This is more of an action
horror thriller to me.
This is like, you have to go
and look for the hidden Area 54.
You know what I mean, this is more like...
Like the closer to reality kind of deal.
You don't even see zombies
for the first half of the movie, which I love.
It's really about the actors,
it's about the tension.
Well, we figured,
if you come see Resident Evil,
you know you're gonna go see the undead.
You know they're coming.
So there's no reason to shove them in
your face in the first minute of the movie.
She was underwater
for a long time doing that, wasn't she?
- Yeah. She had to learn how to scuba dive.
- She had such a bad day that day.
You're feeling sorry for her.
That's actually just
a dummy in the background.
I thought it was my sister.
Oh, they touched. Oh, more ways than one.
James Purefoy,
doesn't he look like James Bond?
Hey, did you enjoy that, Milla?
She's like, "Yeah."
Bond Purefoy.
I am Bond.
That's great. That's perfect.
Hey, let's talk over the voices.
Nothing before the train.
And you?
No. Nothing.
James Purefoy, who was in a film called...
Hey, he partied hard with us, man, he rules.
Yeah, he rocks. He can party.
Who's James Purefoy? Jesus Christ.
He played the black prince
in A Knight's Tale.
He took his pants off at a club with Jeremy.
Who's James Purefoy?
The difference is he put them on again.
One of Jeremy's important jobs
as a producer on this movie
was to take the actors
out to various Berlin clubs.
We took him out.
What are you talking about?
- It's a hard job, but somebody has to do it.
- I found it very difficult.
Jeremy's like,
"What are you guys doing? I'll go."
Michelle, that's our secret.
There's a very famous club
in Berlin called the Kit Kat Club,
where you have to check your trousers
at the door, is that correct?
That's where the black
under James Purefoy's eyes came from.
It's true, you have to take your clothes off
except for your underwear.
- And all the actors wanted to go there.
- Not the girls that are dressed appropriately.
So, anyway I...
I heard you and Michelle had some
nice leather undergarments that night.
Well, that's the thing,
if you're wearing fly leather pants,
you don't have to take them off.
For any guy that ever wondered if Michelle
wears leather undergarments, yes, she does.
I had a leather bra on. Give me a break.
Of course she does,
what else would she wear? Jesus Christ.
- It was very cool.
- It's like heavy metal.
This is Germany. This is what happens
when you're not working.
You gotta party.
This is sick, I like the way...
And by the way, there's guys with strings
on each side of the door
to open it up, which I find very cool.
Yeah, those doors are incredibly high tech.
It's behind the wood
that looks exactly like cement.
So great.
This is a great scene.
This was a really, really
difficult set to shoot in.
Because these boxes in the background,
we only had a dozen of them,
we only had about 12 or 15 of them.
And they're all on wheels.
So, every time we do a reverse here,
every time we change angles,
you're basically seeing the same boxes,
but we had to push them around.
So, we made the whole
place look like a labyrinth,
but it certainly wasn't easy.
Now, this was one of the sets that Paul
found very difficult, to the extent that,
on our first trip there,
we went back to the drawing board.
The designer had gotten it slightly wrong.
So, it was one of those really
stressful moments as a producer, because...
Paul really wasn't happy,
and when Paul's really unhappy
he goes very quiet,
he doesn't have a Michael Bay tantrum,
he goes really quiet and white.
And I knew something had to be done.
Because he was rigid with rage.
- There's whiter than that, then?
- I'm quite white to start with.
And he's pretty white to start with.
And we had 24 hours.
Fortunately our designer,
who really hadn't paid attention to the set,
really pulled it out
of the bag at the last minute.
And it works great.
- But it was a really, really stressful 24 hours.
- Wet paint all over the place.
He had all these beer tanks
there for some reason.
- Yeah, it didn't look good to start with.
- No.
But, a lot of these boxes
you see in the background,
we had the dozen
nice ones for the foreground,
a lot of them in the background
are actually cardboard cut-outs.
Which... Everyone thought
we were insane when we were doing it.
It's like, "You can't just have
cardboard cut-outs in the background,
"they're going to look rubbish."
But, the way it's lit, you just can't tell.
- My DP's called David Johnson.
- He's another party guy.
He was a party guy. He was cool.
And this is the second movie
I've done with him.
And he again showed
a great appreciation of the game.
Like, in the game there are
lots of overhead shots
that are signature shots to the game.
And we tried to recreate those.
So, he was always looking for
ways to shoot the movie
in ways that resembled the game.
There's always this feeling
that you're being watched
when you play the video game,
I think that you captured that very well.
And also the game is structured around,
you're always opening doors,
going through doors,
and we wanted to do pretty much
the same with the movie.
Although, for budgetary reasons,
they're actually going through
the same door nearly all the time.
This door here we used
about 12 times in the movie.
- It's all good, it looks different.
- It's just repainted each time.
Now, this was literally
the first week of shooting.
I mean, second week for you guys,
but the first week with the principal actors.
Yeah. What did we do the first week?
There was all the lab stuff.
Oh, yeah, that's right.
You guys were in boot camp
when we did that.
Was that boot camp useful?
This was the first day for me,
are you kidding?
No, your first day was in the mansion.
Outside the mansion.
Yeah, but that didn't count.
Because that was just me walking...
Hey, this was a professional,
like, he had to do this
about 100 times to get it straight.
- Poor Colin was so exhausted.
- It's all about the commando walk, man.
It was so hot in there, too.
With all that stuff
you guys had on, Jesus Christ.
I remember Colin the next day,
"God, I'm in so much pain, I didn't know
that you had to do this so many times."
He looks so good, though.
Yeah, he totally looks like a commando.
- He should be Bond.
- I mean, he shouldn't die.
- He would like to be Bond.
- I wish he got a bigger...
I keep saying for part two you have to
clone Michelle and Colin
and bring them back.
He's a smooth Bond.
You mean they die in the movie?
- You've given it away.
- Well, they've seen the movie already.
- Hopefully.
- Sometimes.
And look, if you're reading the
commentaries before watching the movie,
you should be disappointed
with me telling you what happens.
Checkmate.
Actually, I never went to...
Like, the last time I shot a real gun
was in my dad's backyard,
with a shotgun and almost breaking my arm
falling to the ground at the age of 12.
Were you aiming at your dad?
No, I was aiming at a can
and it ended up going somewhere else,
probably somebody's house over there
or the barn next door or something.
Yeah, but...
I learned a lot about guns.
I was pretty much a natural. It was cool.
.45's got some kickback.
That gun I think is my favourite
out of all the guns that were used,
the one that Colin's holding.
It actually shoots missiles up to 300 yards.
Actually shoots little missiles,
rockets come out of that sucker.
And it's a machine gun.
They're stuntmen, not actors, those two.
God, I guess,
when I was a teenager I'd definitely gone
to the shooting range every once in a while,
then when I did Fifth Element
I did some gun training.
And since The Fifth Element
it was pretty much
like every once in a while
again at the shooting range,
but on this movie I really
had somebody to help me
understand exactly how to use a gun.
But, kind of like what Michelle said,
it kind of came very naturally.
You know, I can't make
a basket to save my life,
but if you let me shoot the ball, I'll get it.
Oh, God, that's so sick.
Half his crotch got cut off there.
But I'm so proud of Marc,
because he was one of the stunt guys,
and he's totally in the movie,
I think that's so awesome.
I love this part.
It's like, "Yeah, come on, get me."
It's so great to hear.
Colin ordinarily has an English accent,
and it's so cool to hear him
speak like an American.
Shit.
It's like, "Shit," instead of, "Shit."
How do you guys say it? Come on, guys.
Shit.
- No, no, no. How do you...
- We don't swear in England.
Yes you do.
They say, "Tits."
- They sound very civilised.
- Paul, would you like to talk about Cube?
I haven't seen Cube,
I don't know what you're talking about.
Neither have of us have seen Cube.
We've heard about it but never seen it.
- What's Q?
- Cube.
Cube.
It's this really cool
low budget art horror movie.
- Yeah.
- And they have a guy chopped up in it.
Cubed.
This is our little homage to Cube.
We think Cube is one of the great
horror movies of the last few years.
I thought you were talking about the rapper.
- I love him. I think he's so great, Martin.
- He's a really good singer, as well.
He's amazing, Martin, and he looks
like a total movie star.
Yeah, he is.
We had to pluck
his eyebrows for the movie, though.
He has the most outrageous big eyebrows.
Paul did that himself, personally.
How come you guys don't mention that we
were all supposed to be characters of the,
what was it, Alice in Wonderland?
- Because you weren't, though.
- Not really.
Well, at first, you wanted to...
Yeah, Paul, it was you.
You gave us all Alice in Wonderland books.
And then all of a sudden
you ditched the idea at the end.
We had Tweedledum, Tweedledee,
the Rabbit's right there, look at him,
he's always worried about time,
and then Alice, of course.
I mean, you were Tweedledum.
I was Tweedledee.
- I was Tweedledee.
- J.D. was Tweedledum.
- Of course he was, 'cause he's not here.
- You better stop it before I shove your head
into my armpits.
I didn't wear deodorant today.
- Who was the Mad Hatter?
- The thing I love the best about my job
is to get to put my head
into Michelle's armpits.
- It's all good.
- It turns me on.
It's all about that European scent.
It's the musk.
Especially from an American.
That European smell is great.
Yeah. You spent so much time there
you thought you were one.
Oh, totally, man. Let the hair grow.
Give me a hand with this.
Hey, what really is that?
That's one of those lights
- that you use at the clubs, isn't it?
- Yeah.
- Disco light.
- It's a disco light.
And there's the Red Queen.
Get out! Get out! You can't be in here.
I love her voice. "Can't be in here."
- She's very creepy.
- Well, thank God they used her voice
- because for a month there they had...
- We used an American.
...changed the real girl's voice
for an American because
there was talk that people couldn't
understand her English accent.
And literally... I mean, no offence to
the young girl they got who did a great job,
but she sounded so sexually insinuating.
And the Red Queen, you know,
all she does is talk.
And she talks and talks about
kind of technical stuff
and to hear a child saying technical stuff
in this sort of voice,
just like "I've been a bad, bad girl."
- That's sort of perverse there, guys.
- I heard this. I was, like, "No way!
- "This is completely pornographic."
- Who directed that little girl?
- I know, honestly. Hello.
- I did. Sorry.
Oh, God, Paul, no!
- It was kind of Lolita, wasn't it?
- What's this, what's this?
That's the brain of the creature.
- Oh, for a second there...
- The brain of the licker.
...it looked like a scene out of Ghost...
- Ghost?
- No, no, no, wait, wait.
- I don't remember that scene in Ghost.
- The clay, the clay, the pottery wheel.
- No, there's this Japanimation...
- Oh, Ghost in the Shell.
- Ghost in the Shell.
Very cool. Watch Ghost in the Shell
and see where The Matrix came from.
Yeah, that, too. But that, I think
The Matrix is a mixture
of Ghost in the Shell and this book called
And The Truth Shall Set You Free.
- Oh, yeah.
- 'Cause that book, if you read
the first couple of chapters in it, it's just...
It even uses the words
"Zarragnarok", and...
- And the name of the ship and everything.
- I love this set.
It's just too much.
Those guys are cool. Biters.
They got that off. I like them.
- Who made this?
- Richard Bridgland.
It's a big chip in the image of a chess set,
isn't it?
How cool is that? How cool is that?
Cleaning your nails with a big knife.
Oh, man, I would've liked to cut
a zombie or two up with it,
- but no.
- All the way through the movie,
I was trying to figure out a way
for Michelle to use that knife
- and it's a big regret that we never...
- I wanted to cut somebody.
- He wouldn't let me.
- I've got to ask Paul,
what is Eric doing up there
and how did he get there?
Michelle put him up there.
I just threw him up there, you know?
I said, "Here, sit."
- That was really masterful direction.
- I know. It would have been really great
- to see that happen.
- That was Eric.
- Eric wanted to sit there.
- Eric never went to the gym once.
No, no, no, if I recall this scene correctly,
the reason why he sat up there is because
you wanted him to look like that crazy worm
that smokes in the...
- The caterpillar.
- In Alice in Wonderland.
- The caterpillar in Alice in Wonderland.
- What? What?
- Yes.
- I know, it's a bit deep.
- What?
- Okay.
Michelle just blew up...
- I'm never going to forget that.
- I never forgot it.
He said it, and I was, like, "Whoa."
The repressed art school dreams
that never happened
- are coming out here.
- Yeah, watch.
There's loads of Alice in Wonderland
in this movie.
You've got the Red Queen,
she chops lots of people's heads off.
You've got a girl called Alice
who goes through a looking glass.
Wench.
- This is...
- See, you should have let me
use my knife here, Paul,
but you don't like, you know, details.
I totally wanted to cut her up.
You know, pull her spleen out or something.
Yeah, actually. You know what?
We should've got you to use your knife.
Yeah, but, no. Nobody let me.
It was too much.
- We don't have any knife. Knife death is...
- No knife fight.
It was too much, making guts and stuff,
you know?
You had to make the guts for me
to pull it out of her, you know?
For the sequel, Paul,
we need some knife action.
It would have been nice,
but I do like how she dies, though.
- Or seems to die.
- He's great, J.D.
- Bitch isn't standing now.
- That's right, damn it.
Take it. That's it.
- Kneecapped.
- Kneecap.
We had zombie boot camp.
- The dancers.
- Yeah, most of the zombies were dancers
'cause we wanted people who had control
over their bodies,
so that, you know,
everyone wasn't doing their own
kind of zombie schtick in the background.
So, we probably had, like, 600 people
went to zombie boot camp.
- And out of that...
- Including me.
Yeah, Jeremy's in the movie a lot.
He'll be appearing as a zombie a lot.
- Any second.
- So we trained all the people how to move.
You can really tell the difference
between the dancer zombies
and the Jeremy zombies
because Jeremy does not look like a dancer
- when he dies.
- I'm a producer!
- I found it really difficult.
- Just watch the film
- and just see if you know where Jeremy is.
- Jeremy's a lot more stiff, you know?
He's very English in his mannerisms
as a zombie, you know?
I was just over on assignment
from the London office.
- That's coagulated blood.
- Well, Jeremy's been trying to appear
in our movies for 10 years now,
and usually he has
a little walk-on role and they always have to
cut it out 'cause he's so stiff
and such a bad actor, and finally
we made the movie where he's perfect.
You know, he's just a perfect undead 'cause
that's how he moves around normally.
You know, Jeremy, you're simply perfect.
You're just perfect.
Perfect undead.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Now, this is great, this.
This guy you're about to see,
dragging his heel,
is a very, very good dancer.
And he can actually dislocate his foot,
which is why this looks so weird.
- Oh, fuck off!
- His ankle.
- And his shoulder is dislocated as well.
- He popped his shoulder
and took his foot out of his ankle.
- He can also twist his wrist off.
- He's great.
- I like him.
- He's a real bendy man.
He's very cool.
Oh, my God. Damn, Milla.
That's my favourite. I like it.
- "I like it."
- I like it.
- I like the way that you added the whole...
- Bond is scared.
What did you guys do?
I mean, did you put blue on their faces
- or something to do that?
- We did many, many things.
I guess Richard will explain that.
I'd like to see it, actually.
Do I have to buy the DVD,
or will you give me one?
No, we don't give you one.
You have to buy it.
- That sucks, man.
- It's 30 bucks.
- Here you go, Michelle.
- Look at that. Every movie I made,
I don't have one DVD from any
of the movies.
I refuse!
No, no, I think if you check your contract,
I think we have to give you one, actually.
I shouldn't have to pay. That's it.
I refuse to pay for a DVD that I'm in.
So, Michelle has no DVDs
of any of her films!
I have none. None. I've done five movies
already, I don't have one.
Yeah, because every film,
it's like, "No, you will pay."
And she's like,
"No, I won't. Screw you guys."
- That's Jeremy! Wasn't that you?
- I don't think so.
- No, that wasn't you?
- That was a dancer.
- Oh, you know, yeah. He wasn't that stiff.
- All the jiggling.
I should have known.
Okay, let's see if... Can we spot Jeremy?
All right.
Look for a balding guy.
There's a couple of 'em here, though.
I know. Just look for...
Well, we ended up shaving more and more
of Jeremy's hair off so he didn't seem
like the same zombie dying
over and over again.
Jeremy, you morphed, though,
during the shooting, because you were
all pudgy in the beginning,
and then, all of a sudden,
you started to transform
and work out and start doing all this stuff,
and the next thing you know,
by the end of the shooting process,
he was all fit and shit.
- Thank you, Michelle.
- No, it's true, man.
You underwent a metamorphosis
of some sort.
- It was something about Berlin.
- No, you thought you were the licker.
- That's what it was.
- Yeah, a mutation.
Yes. He wanted to be the licker,
but they wouldn't let him
'cause he wasn't tall enough.
- Or his tongue wasn't long enough.
- That, too.
- It's good music. Good Manson music.
- I feel like I'm in a club.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, if only all clubs were this fun.
Give you some guns at the door.
- That was Jeremy, wasn't it?
- No.
No.
This stunt man was amazing.
We set this guy on fire 25 times.
Look at this. Jurassic Park ride.
Now, I'm about to appear.
- It's bated breath here.
- This looks like a music video.
Listen, Michelle, you can come over
to my place, we can do makeup.
Oh, God, girly time. No!
I'll come.
- That sounded rehearsed, Jeremy.
- 'Cause Michelle likes man time.
- She does it all the time.
- Yeah, you know, you missed
Jeremy Bolt's big appearance.
He just got shot.
- That's so not true.
- I come up again, though.
Just for that, Milla,
I'm wearing a skirt to the premiere.
- Are you?
- No.
- Just because you were talking shit.
- I am not talking shit.
I think you're one
of the hottest chicks around.
- So do I.
- Oh, thank you, I think you're hot, too.
- I like you, Michelle. I wanna fuck you.
- Stop!
- There I am! You missed me!
- Now that we've finally been able... Oh.
- Milla, you missed my death.
- Sorry.
- It was quite good.
- Oh, can you rewind that?
- Excuse me, Michelle has finally given me
the time of day,
I gotta take advantage of the situation.
- It was a stiff death.
- Rewind that.
We'll see Jeremy again.
He's got one more scene coming up.
Oh, right. Right here, if I'm correct.
- Yep.
- You bite somebody's arm.
- Is that my arm?
- Yeah, I was biting yours.
- Somebody's luscious arm.
- Yeah.
- My scar-infested arm.
- Now, those of you who have seen
- Day of the Dead...
- I still have have marks. Look.
- Yes.
- ...the Romero movie,
will remember this scene
- 'cause we pretty much stole it.
- Yes. A bit of homage.
- Yes, homage and not theft.
- More of a homage.
- Hey, I look like I'm really, really...
- There I am!
- There I am! There I am!
- There he is! That's Jeremy!
- Again.
- Yep. Biting a big black thing.
Excuse me.
Like, what I don't understand is
why I didn't start elbowing the people
that were pulling me away, and just took
my knife out and started stabbing.
That's my best friend, you know.
Who cares about you guys?
That's my friend.
- But, you know, you realised it was useless.
- Yeah.
The zombies would have killed me.
- Bye, J.D.
- So, this is...
- The licker! Yes.
- ...the licker.
His debut. Look at this, ladies
and gentlemen. The luscious licker.
And that's before he's actually
seven feet tall, if I'm correct.
So, Paul, is the licker...
The licker is basically...
You were calling Milla a luscious licker?
Is that what just happened?
No. I was talking for a second.
That was the licker
before he turned into the licker.
- No.
- It's the before and after.
That's before he was seven feet tall.
I was talking about his birth.
You guys just witnessed the birth
of the licker.
He came out of the metal foetus.
- That's very deep, Michelle.
- Yeah, fuck.
That was a wonderful performance.
"Whatever they are,
there are too many of them out there."
This is my favourite line.
We ADR'd this whole movie by the way.
- "People used to work here."
- "These people used to work here."
- "All the people working here are dead."
- Exactly.
"They all go walking around."
- Yo, we do some pretty good...
- That's a great line.
Well done, Bond. A real Bond line.
"You let them out, you stupid rabbit.
You silly rabbit."
He's the rabbit, right?
He's always worried about time.
- "It's time to go. Time to go."
- Who's Spence in the Alice in Wonderland
- allegory?
- Michelle is.
- "You're never gonna make it."
- What?
Who is Spence
in the Alice in Wonderland allegory?
- Michelle?
- I'm Spence?
No. Which figure in Alice in Wonderland
does Spence represent?
Spence, I think he would be
the Cheshire Cat
because nobody knows
what he's really about.
- That was very good.
- Then who's the Mad Hatter?
- Damn, you paid attention to this movie.
- I didn't pay attention to the movie,
but I paid attention to the process
of making it.
Now, this is my favourite scene
in the whole film.
Oh, yes, by the way, I've been getting
so many comments on that luscious kick
- you did. It was amazing.
- Yeah, Milla, that kick...
- That everybody thinks it's you.
- It's the flying kick.
No, Milla, that kick is fantastic.
- It's luscious.
- But these dogs were so well-behaved.
As long as you didn't look them in the eyes.
- Oh, yeah, right, well behaved.
- They were. They didn't poop.
I didn't get it. How come you didn't hear...
You know that noise that a dog makes
when you hit him?
'Cause the zombie dogs
don't make those noises.
- You know that noise.
- What is it?
Are you always hitting dogs?
- No, because, Michelle, we didn't hurt...
- Oh, I hate that.
I used to stick firecrackers up their butts
when I was a kid
- just to watch them blow.
- I think we'll edit that.
I'm joking, man. I would never do harm
to an animal. Dude, come on.
What do you take me for?
I cried during Dumbo, for Christ's sake.
- Did you?
- Well, who didn't cry during Dumbo?
- Jesus Christ.
- I didn't.
A person who sticks firecrackers
up animals' butts.
I think you'll find that Paul and I didn't cry
during Dumbo.
- No, we didn't cry.
- Yeah, you firecracker stickers.
- We cried during Terminator.
- Hey, look at this. That's spaghetti.
That's spaghetti and pizza
all over the dog, by the way.
- That's the secret ingredient.
- And KY Jelly.
Yeah.
- It's a quattro stagioni.
- What is that actually, Paul?
- That's silicone?
- That's secret sauce.
That's a secret recipe. That...
- That went on our burgers afterwards.
- Nice! Nice!
- "Oh, my God."
- Don't they look like that
in the new Resident Evil video game
we saw?
- Oh, look at that!
- Yeah, the dogs are pretty spot on.
- This guy was an ex-Navy SEAL.
- This is Jaymes Butler.
Jaymes Butler, who was one
of our stunt coordinators.
He trained everybody to do this.
He trained Milla.
- He was awesome.
- He taught Milla how to drop-kick like that.
- Hell, yeah.
- He was just an exceptionally good
part of the crew, Jaymes Butler.
Outstanding man.
And yeah, a Navy SEAL.
He made everyone feel very safe,
which was really important.
Hey, hey, look at this moment.
This is when Milla discovers her powers.
- "I have secret powers. I can kick ass."
- Oh, I love this.
But you know what was clever about this?
This was something that really,
in the cutting room, came together.
- What do you mean?
- This is a very Resident Evil style angle,
you know, straight from the game.
What do you mean?
Where were you going to put this scene?
- No, no, the flashback she's about to have...
- Yeah?
...when she remembers her powers,
that was...
You mean the one she just had?
- It was meant for another scene?
- No, no, that was never shot.
That was never intended to be in the movie.
One she just had.
Sorry, I got my English incorrect.
That shot that we just missed...
This is not a great commentary, you guys,
because we always talk about shots, like,
five minutes after they're over.
But the shot you saw, like, two minutes ago
with the dog crashing through the window,
- that's straight from the game.
- Absolutely.
- Yes, yes.
- It's nice.
And that's done practically.
That's a real dog jumping through
a sugar-glass window.
It's cool. Yeah, this is so radical.
How many scenes?
How many times did you have to do this?
This is awesome.
Yeah.
- I like the close-up.
- Umbrella, nine millimetre.
- That's a fabulous shot.
- Nice.
- That's awesome.
- I think that was Jeremy's favourite shot
- in the whole movie.
- How'd you get that dropping?
- And at one point, we were gonna cancel it.
- Yes.
And he just lobbied for it so hard.
Paul just kept saying,
"Well, you should speak to Jeremy."
- I wouldn't let it...
- Yeah!
I was on a wire.
And pretty much most of my training
was for that scene
to get that scene really great.
So I trained about, I guess, what,
in the end, like, three months
to do that sequence,
to jump up the wall and all that.
Do the big drop-kick.
It was one of the funnest scenes
for me to do in the movie
because I look hardcore.
I have a great mini-dress on,
and I'm kicking a dog in the head.
And the sound effects were amazing,
by the way.
- What more do you want?
- You know that sound?
No, but it was also great because
I'm a huge fan of the game,
and the dog sequence is, like...
If you know Resident Evil,
you know about the Dobermans.
They're hard. They're the hardest, I think,
to kill other than the big monsters
that you face.
Yeah, so it was just awesome to be able
to be the girl from the Doberman scene.
It was great.
- What happened there?
- Hi, Kate.
Well, he's off looking for his sister.
- He's looking for his vitamins.
- He's looking for his yoghurt.
"Where's my Wheaties?"
You know, this guy ate so much yoghurt
- he made himself sick.
- He turned white.
Okay, Eric Mabius' breakfast of champions,
yoghurt and a bell pepper.
- Oh, God!
- No.
- Yes, I told him that peppers
are good for your skin,
that some French actress told me.
- You told him that...
- Yeah, so he totally started eating peppers.
- Michelle!
- That's so cool.
- You have influence over people.
- Funniest thing is, the guys on this movie
literally did so much more
than either Michelle or I did health-wise.
I mean, they were so on top
of their physiques.
- They had more time.
- I'm over there eating frankfurters.
- And big, giant cheeseburgers.
- Yeah, we used to have to send out
for burgers for Milla. We used to get
McDonald's and Burger King on set.
- Oh, my God. Yum.
- I don't eat beef.
So that's Heike...
- Hi, brother.
- Great German actress, Heike Makatsch.
- Is she German? I thought she was English.
- No, she's German.
No, she goes out with Daniel Craig,
who was in Tomb Raider.
But she's German.
She's a very big star in Germany.
And that's
an Alice in Wonderland paperweight.
That is so great.
Should've done a close-up on that.
Well, there was a close-up,
but that was cut out.
It's all about the paperweight.
Paperweights.
Yes, was...
I want the paperweight, that's the price.
- Who was she?
- My sister.
Corporations like Umbrella...
It was a very, very tough budget.
We didn't have any real contingency.
Which is why Jeremy's in the movie
so often, due to a lack of stuntmen.
Yeah, that's exactly right.
You know. And...
He's like, "It's okay. I should do this.
And then I don't have to pay myself."
The actors shared cars in the morning.
You know, everyone gave something.
Some of us provide information,
others give their support.
Some take more direct action.
Like you.
If your friends had been
a little more thorough,
they would've seen
right through my false ID.
Then all the red flags would've gone off...
Quantico, NSA, VICAP, all the rest.
There's no way
I could've infiltrated the Hive.
So you sent your sister.
We needed something concrete.
Anything to expose Umbrella to the press.
Proof of the research
that was going on down here.
What kind of research?
The illegal kind.
Genetic.
Viral.
The first time you see the licker in the game
is in Resident Evil 2.
And it's a really great scene
where it's crawling on the ceiling
of a police station and then drops down
on top of you and kills you.
What kind of noises does the licker make?
It makes the noises it makes in the movie.
That kind of... noise.
- What you're asking...
- And what we did was
we recreated that scene
in the railway station
which is a little later in the movie.
He doesn't scream like a pterodactyl
or anything?
No. No. I mean, that's one of the things
the sound designers on the movie did,
was they looked at the game a lot
and wherever possible,
we took sounds from the game
and used it in the movie.
- Yeah.
- So, for example, the first time you ever
meet the dogs in the game,
you don't see the dogs, you hear their...
- Of their claws.
- Yeah, I love that.
And that's exactly how you meet them
in the movie as well.
- Yeah.
- And also there's great sound effects
that you always hear in Resident Evil
of people going up and down metal stairs.
Yeah, yeah.
Which is great, 'cause it's coming up.
In the new Resident Evil
you even have moths.
The next sequence is all underground.
- You can hear the moths hitting the light.
- Oh, wow.
- That's a good idea.
- It's so great.
Did you guys know, actually,
the scene in the beginning with Michelle
looking underground with the flashlight...
- Under the train carriage.
- ...that was insane because the sound guy
actually went and recorded, like,
2,000 cockroaches scuttling.
- Yeah, that noise. That's...
- And that noise you hear, it's...
- It's actually 2,000 cockroaches.
- Nice!
Can I just say, right now,
and I give Paul a lot of shit for this,
but what is that noise?
Can somebody tell me what is it
that Michelle hears
- that sounds like 2,000 cockroaches.
- It's the sound of2,000 cockroaches.
"It's the sound of2,000..."
That's it. That's what's back there.
Cockroaches. And a lot of them.
- What is it?
- Zombie cockroaches.
The other thing we did for some
of the weird noises in the movie is...
What a great profile.
...our sound designer blew wind through...
Michelle's just applauding herself there.
You're admiring your own profile?
What an amazing actress.
...is the only fail-safe plan they had
against possible contamination.
One of the things our sound designer did
was he blew wind
through chicken carcasses
and pig carcasses.
But the chickens were dead
when he blew the wind through.
They weren't alive. No animals were harmed
during the making of this film.
Other than the actors.
And frankly, they deserved it.
And the people around him.
- Where are you taking those?
- I'm turning her back on.
That is not a good idea.
I love that corridor, by the way.
- It's epic for me.
- Where did you get the idea
- for that corridor, Paul?
- He's a sick puppy, that's where he got it.
No, no, I was watching an art movie
called Goya in Bordeaux.
Yeah?
- The products or the painter?
- The painter.
And... 'Cause we were really stuck
as to what to do with that corridor
'cause we knew we wanted something
that looked really different and spectacular.
But I was, like... I had no idea what to do.
And I was watching this art movie
and there's a great corridor in it
that's made out of
just, kind of, black plastic bags
laid on the floor and up the walls
and on the ceiling, so it was really cheap,
you could tell.
'Cause it was an art movie,
they didn't have much money to spend.
How the hell do you go from plastic bags
to a reflective...
- Well, it was very, very reflective.
- It was like black reflection.
You know, it was, like, a whole corridor
made out of black oil,
- like reflective oil.
- That must've looked great.
And that gave me the idea to then,
you know, make it a mirrored corridor.
Yeah, it's actually quite a cool film,
that Goya in Bordeaux.
I think that's great,
how he used reflection a lot in this film.
I think it's very important,
'cause you scare yourself with reflections.
- Yeah.
- It's just kind of sick,
just not knowing what it really is
that you're looking at.
- Well, one of the...
- Yeah, and that's so important. Sorry, Paul.
One of the things we wanted to do
with this movie was go back
to how horror movies and scary movies
used to be made
before CG,
before you could actually show creatures.
You know, you had to hide them,
like in Ridley Scott's Alien.
You know, he had a rubbish monster.
He had a guy in a bad rubber suit.
So he ended up having to hide the guy
in the rubber suit
and the end effect is terrifying
because you can't really see what it is,
and it's really scary and your mind fills in
the blanks.
And I think that's one of the things
we tried to do as much as possible.
Obviously, we have CG monsters,
but we tried not to show them.
For the longest time, to hold back
and not show them,
so the audience could kind of go,
"What was that? What did I see there?"
Yeah, 'cause I think a lot of mistakes
that are made with scary movies
these days is the fact
that you always see the monster.
You see too much.
Severing the top of the spinal column
or massive trauma to the brain
are the most effective methods.
You mean shoot them in the head.
Yeah, Milla is a workaholic.
I've got to say she's the hardest working
actor I've ever worked with.
On this movie, she's working six-day weeks,
she was training on her seventh day,
and the one time we gave her a weekend off,
she went and shot a L'Oréal commercial.
It's almost impossible to kill.
I couldn't allow it to escape from the Hive,
so I took steps.
- Steps.
- You must understand.
Those who become infected,
I can't allow you to leave.
Whoa. We're not infected.
Just one bite, one scratch
from these creatures is sufficient...
This right here is when the audience
knows I'm going to die.
Or has an idea that I am going
to turn into a zombie.
- No.
- Oh, yeah.
I wish it would have happened
earlier and I had
more of my brain than all the other zombies.
Then I could, like, strategically attack
you guys throughout the movie.
Would have been so much more fun.
Oh, like we wouldn't have killed you?
That depends, you see, if I got half a brain,
then at least, you know, I can
out-think you guys.
- Yeah.
- It's great, 'cause here...
Here you go into a completely
different environment,
which again is something that
we took from the game.
This was a set that we constructed.
Oh, it's all about the underground, man.
- What the hell is this place?
- The utility tunnels.
They run underneath the Hive
for water, gas and power lines.
I love James. He's really being cautious.
- He is so brave.
- Hey, whoa.
He's so brave.
I love that bit. That was great.
You totally cut that out. It was so funny.
James did this great spin turn.
Yeah, that was quite...
This bit's good.
Remember that day, Michelle?
"Those things are...
Shit, okay one more time.
"You gotta keep moving
because those, right...
"Shit, okay, one more time."
It's like...
- Here we go.
- Paul, your brilliant dialogue.
- I like the sound effects.
- Hey, leave my dialogue alone.
So this was the scene,
the first time that Milla ever punched me.
We were blocking this scene.
I remember that. That was funny.
And I was standing in
for one of the zombies.
She turned around and she just,
I got this fantastic right hook.
- Right in the eye.
- She almost totally cracked everybody.
And then, about a week later, she...
She punched my director of photography.
So we're both walking around
with black eyes.
Take it down.
Here, is it your agent?
No, it's actually right there.
Ah, that was beautiful.
That's that slow neck cracking. I like that.
That guy, he just wanted
to do that over and over again.
He took a pounding, man.
You kidding? He loved that.
So how do you slow it down like that?
I mean...
- Oh, it's quite expensive.
- That's nice.
It's quite expensive, yeah.
- Use a lot of film.
- Oh, man.
- So you speed it up then?
- Well, some of it is optical. You just...
If you wanna make it slow,
you double print all the frames.
What happened to Jeremy's
girlfriend's cleavage on this?
'Cause I remember
that the whole purpose
of that shot right there.
That, by the way, that...
The undead biting Kaplan's thigh
is my girlfriend.
Yeah, but what happened, the whole reason
for getting Janie to do that was because
it was supposed to be sexy,
man, and you totally covered her cleavage.
Well, no, I didn't direct it, I just...
It was all slimy and had, like,
pus all over it. It was perfect.
The sexiest zombie ever.
Totally, and they didn't use it.
- The most glamorous zombie ever.
- I walked into set one morning and I said
- to Paul, "We need to sex up the undead."
- She had radical sores on her breasts.
Sex up the undead.
He said, "Your girlfriend has just arrived.
"She can be one, she can show...
"Show some of her breast."
She, of course, didn't think...
Thought she was going to do it topless,
and would have been happy to.
- In French.
- What happened, man?
Yeah, Janie is giving Jeremy
a look right now.
- Doesn't have to be PG.
- He is going to pay for that comment.
It's rated R.
You can get away with anything, almost.
I can think of things
you can't get away with.
Yeah, I am sure you can.
- Censorship sucks.
- This is actually my second favourite scene.
I thought that that should
have been the poster.
- You and...
- Not me and Michelle.
- You?
- That shot of Michelle.
It should be you with your hair
in slow motion.
Yeah.
Holding a big, giant gun.
No, that is a nice shot, the overhead.
So, we built a camera track into
this set which is quite nice.
He had to hang this on the pipes
above Eric there.
- Yeah.
- We did that with a lot of the sets.
We did it in the glass corridor as well.
There is a camera track
built in there, that's...
You know, you see it all the way
through the scene, but
it's disguised,
so you don't realise what it is.
Nice.
You can't get more Resident Evil than this.
- Yes, this is one of my favourite sets.
- That's for shizzle.
And this was...
This scene has the one stunt in it
that Milla was not allowed to do.
The insurance company wouldn't
allow her to do it.
Otherwise she does absolutely...
All the girls do all their own
stunts in the movie.
And it's the bit where
the pipes collapse and she has to jump
to the far wall, and Eric catches her.
And the reason why she couldn't do it was
all those cables that you see
hanging there were released
and there was a risk that
the cable would fall
and maybe wrap around somebody's neck.
- Surely.
- And strangle my lead actress.
That's what your stunt doubles are for.
So there's the shot that I am not in.
That's it, and then you're back.
That's true.
- It's true.
- Thank you.
Thanks for the backup.
Shit.
Well, it's just she did all her own stunts
except for that. That's pretty good.
I mean, at the start of the movie we were...
Can we just get a round of applause?
Thank you.
Can I get a gold star next to my name?
Yes, I think you could.
So long as it doesn't cost too much.
I hate vulnerable moments, by the way,
and this was my most vulnerable one.
- Well, why can't you...
- I can't see.
Why can't you see?
'Cause your hair is in your eyes.
I got bit too many times.
- So your vision is becoming blurry?
- Yes.
It was the night before.
- Yeah.
- Partying too much.
- Where was Roman?
- I can't remember my lines.
I can't get the scene over with.
- Are you sure?
- Roman?
Hey, look, the bunny is cornered.
Yeah, my genius plan.
Hold on!
- I'll sort it out, don't worry.
- Okay.
- It'll be okay.
- Let me just tell you guys that this is all
improv and what my genius plan was,
was to cut one of those wires,
throw it over, and have
somebody shimmy across.
- It was good thinking.
- That's a pretty good idea.
- Like.
- Not that bad.
Yeah, Paul.
It's too much, he's like,
"It's too much coverage."
Actually, Jeremy is there like, "No, no, no."
They're like, "Sure."
- Yeah, the guys can't wait to leave.
- They're like, "Goodbye."
James is so brave.
Now, this zombie here,
that's on Martin's foot,
this is one of the guys who you saw
right at the start of the movie in the lab.
- Yeah.
- The lab that was flooding.
Yeah, but it'd be hard to remember him,
'cause you cut...
- Yeah.
- I think he's...
I don't know.
I don't think anyone recognises him.
This is what I don't understand, Paul.
- There's only one thing?
- Why did you give it away right afterwards?
Yeah, that's what I said.
- I don't get it.
- No, 'cause it's an emotional moment.
You think he's blown his brains out.
Well, good, let us think he blew
his brains out, then we see him.
- Michelle, we discussed it a lot.
- What happened?
We decided to do it this way.
I love him.
- He's great, he's like Ratboy.
- He's creepy.
I think that is a great Martin moment
right there, though.
He was so, like, filled with fear,
it looked like he was about to pee.
Oh, my God, and how funny
were the set pictures?
When we were looking at all those pictures,
it really looked like
Resident Evil: The Musical.
- Yes.
- 'Cause it was like...
It was like Les Misérables.
- Yeah, all these hands reaching up.
- It was all that ice on the pipes,
- and the hands, and Martin...
- It was so like Les Misérables.
...on that thing, going, "No,"
and it looks like he's like,
"No, you must leave, I must stay alone."
No way, that's so bad.
- Oh, this is...
- Now this is a very...
This is great.
- This is...
- I love Eric's reaction to...
Banana and berries.
Wait, listen.
What was that, Michelle?
Banana and berries?
How come you didn't get a close-up
on the throw-up, man?
- This is good.
- Yeah, I love Eric's, "Whoa!"
That's was nice throw-up right there.
I didn't see this shot.
- Oh, yeah.
- So what is...
- I haven't seen this movie.
- That was nice, that was nice.
The reflection.
When I get out of here
I think I'm gonna get laid.
Yeah. You might want
to clean up a little bit first.
I remember talking to Paul about this
before we did it
and I was really unsure of
how it was gonna look.
What, the flashback?
- With the motion control?
- With the motion control.
Everyone hated me for this
'cause this was the first shot
we did in the whole movie,
and it was a motion control shot
and it took all morning.
It took hours and hours.
And everyone just thought,
"We're doomed now.
"'Cause it's taken them the whole morning
to get one shot."
But you have to do all the multiple passes,
you know, you've got to do
Milla by herself, the corridor by itself.
- All these people walking by themselves.
- Right.
How do you guys do that?
- It wasn't overlapping.
- If you listen to the commentary...
If you listen to the commentary with
Richard Yuricich, it will all be explained.
When you buy your DVD, Michelle.
Damn it, I hate the fact that
I have to pay for my own DVD.
- That sucks.
- And also Paul, the Manson
music here is terrific.
'Cause it's all about Manson,
and that's it then.
That wasn't a real rabbit, by the way.
What happened to the Nine Inch Nails song?
That was a real rabbit.
- The Nine Inch Nails track was over...
- That was a real rabbit?
Yeah, but we didn't inject it.
We couldn't afford to put
Nine Inch Nails over this.
Why did you freaking lie to me?
You guys said it was a fake rabbit.
Why? Is it more expensive for
this scene than the other?
No, we could only afford
one Nine Inch Nails track.
- No, no, no.
- So we choose to
put Nine Inch Nails on the dog sequence.
Oh, I liked it on that sequence.
The Nine Inch Nails.
- On this one?
- Yeah, there.
That goop, by the way,
inside that anti-virus thing is soap.
I can't remember,
I think the track was Pinion.
No, but...
We wanted to...
We could only use one Nine Inch Nails track.
- There's hope.
- We had to use Fist Fuck.
- Cause it was the best title.
- He said Fist Fuck.
That's disgusting. That sounds German.
Yeah, it sounds like the name
of one of our ADs.
Fist Fuck.
Hello, Fist Fuck.
Hi, Fist Fuck.
This is great.
Actually, I think James did...
The acting here is pretty good, as well.
- Well done, actors.
- Yeah, you guys did well here.
- The reflections on their faces are great.
- Stop it.
This was all done...
This was all done with mirrors.
It was like a big tray
with mirrors and water in it.
We bounced the light off that
on to the actors' faces.
- This was really, I mean...
- This was around the L'Oréal commercial.
It was really unpleasant for you guys,
wasn't it?
- And we were working really...
- No, it's very pleasant for us.
- I remember the hours were bad.
- This water was freezing cold.
I kept having to ask you
if we could go longer. And longer.
Hey, did you see Eric grope
my breast just there?
- No.
- You can't rewind that bit.
- Did you see that?
- Did he grope your breast?
- He totally groped my breast.
- I think he had a bit of a crush on you.
- No, he didn't.
- Yeah, I think he did.
We were totally bumping heads all the time.
I love that guy, he's cool.
He is cool.
- So where is it?
- It's dying.
It's gone, it's not here.
I don't understand why she
didn't blow her brains out by now, like,
once you can't shoot any more it's like...
- Well, I mean, you don't wanna...
- ...kill yourself already, girl, like...
- 'Cause she wanted she wanted you to be...
- You have one more great scene coming up.
This is Bond, Bond flashback.
Am using my special,
special Bond equipment.
- To eavesdrop on you.
- And how funny is this going to
look in, like, 10, 15 years. Like so low-tech.
What, that microphone?
Like the Red Queen lights.
Oh, my God, completely.
We'll all be looking back and going,
"Can you imagine?"
"People used to watch flat TVs
instead of holograms?"
- Look, handwriting...
- Totally massive error.
Yeah, totally different.
No one will notice. The music is too loud.
- Ah, that was him.
- Now you see that it wasn't me.
Now you see it, now you don't.
- It's the Cheshire Cat back there.
- Actually if you go back and look
at the start of the movie,
you can see that the guy
who is operating those handles is actually
wearing a mask,
someone completely different.
He looks so cool in the leatherjacket, man.
He totally loved that jacket.
- I think he took it.
- He said, "Why do I have to give it to Milla?"
And those are actually his jeans.
No, they really are. They're his own jeans.
- Not from wardrobe.
- Well, that just shows how
committed we were as actors.
He wouldn't wear our jeans,
had to wear his own.
That was his choice, Jeremy.
- It's 501.
- It was okay.
This performance, he needed his own jeans.
- It was important for his character.
- Jeans, 501, Levi's.
- Oh, this is great.
- So, this is it.
This is where Milla becomes soaking.
And makes the decision
to spend half the movie
freezing cold.
Yeah, Milla did that jump herself,
I remember that.
- Just to get the wet mini-dress.
- Did that hurt, when you did that?
- No, it was very cold.
- Impressive.
Because the water was heated
and then we added tea,
- tea in it?
- Yeah, right, heated.
Hello, condensation, my friend.
Yeah, you can catch
yeast infections like that.
We did heat the water but it was still cold.
I know, I was a little worried.
We also tested it every half-hour.
We obviously tested the water
every half an hour.
What did they do to it? They put...
- Coffee and tea?
- No, it was emia.
What?
- Yeah right.
- It was tea.
It was tea, it was English breakfast tea.
It's all about English breakfasts.
Well, I thought it would keep you
perky and awake.
Swimming around in all that caffeine.
Seeps into your pores
and goes to your brain.
And the funniest thing is, like,
we go from here to
the catering tent,
and they'd have disco music playing.
- Abba, they had Abba playing.
- Let's go dancing.
- Yeah.
- They had all that euro funk.
Yeah, I just wanted to go
on holiday with those caterers.
- They're like gypsies, man.
- They look like they had a really good time.
- Yeah, they're...
- That guy, the big guy looked like Obelix.
I can't wait to get out of here
and go eat some yoghurt.
That's Eric's motivation for every scene.
Okay, Eric there is yoghurt
behind that door.
- Go for it.
- That door right there?
Yoghurt. Must get yoghurt.
When I'm undead, I'm having...
And there's my sister coming up again.
- Well done, Anna.
- Oh, look at the nips, man.
Yeah, they...
What happened there, man?
I told you, that's proof that
the water was cold.
- So don't try to, you know...
- No, it's true.
No, I was trying to explain to you it wasn't.
See, Michelle doesn't actually have nipples.
No, they're... I'm totally nipple-less.
- Are you?
- Yes, I'm a hermaphrodite.
- Right.
- Hermaphrodites don't have nipples.
I thought something was weird last night.
You know Eric was pissed about that,
right there.
- Yeah, that he got beaten down so fast.
- There is no way that that flabby guy
is just gonna elbow me
and I am gonna drop.
- I mean, I know.
- And, you know, not be heard from again.
- That's bullshit.
- Well, Eric was just waiting?
But it is kinda true,
that look, too, you know.
- But it's all good.
- He was so pumped, Eric, he was...
He can lift a lot of weight. He really can.
- He's like, "I'll bench-press you."
- Yeah, where is Eric?
Like... Oh, there he is.
He was hurt, he was on the ground,
and he was hurt.
- He was winded.
- He doesn't like being hurt.
And now he's really upset.
- But yo, he's...
- Your boyfriend is a real asshole.
- Yeah.
- He looks like he's going to be powerful.
Soon.
Not in this movie, but soon.
So, like, the other girl was like,
"I don't think so.
"I've been a bad, bad girl."
- So I should just say that...
- I think American
little girls have been kind of, in the business
have been just poisoned, little children.
I'm not saying she was poisoned in any way.
Just saying that American girls
are probably a little bit more mature.
Mature? You think wearing makeup
and trying to sound sexy is mature?
I quite enjoy it.
Come on, oh, my God, Jeremy,
it's a little girl we're talking about here.
No, I know.
Cut that.
Everyone was really impressed
in this scene, that...
Eric was... I mean, Eric...
James had to shoot up.
- James was like, "Wow."
- It's all about heroin.
He was very quick at that.
Yeah, he's the master.
"Oh, don't worry, I don't need to rehearse."
- Yeah.
- Yeah, I'm fine.
He was also very good at being
eaten by the licker.
So this is the moment we tried
to recreate from the game.
- Okay.
- So there it's on a different...
Different kind of ceiling,
these are the same shots.
Oh, that is beautiful.
- So.
- Yeah.
Richard said that that was like
6,000 man hours right there,
those six seconds.
- Yeah, it was big.
- Probably.
There were some frames
of the CG of the creature,
that would literally take, like, one frame,
and there are 24 frames in a second,
for one frame it would take 48 hours
for the computer to render one frame.
Now, this scene coming up...
Not this scene,
but the scene after this scene.
- We understand.
- Really?
Yes, morph, become more powerful,
you luscious creature, you.
"Stronger, faster hunter."
Now, this is where I shoot myself,
by the way.
"I didn't think any of you could..."
You stop cracking, all right?
I thought that little girl did a great job.
No, I think she is so adorable.
Are you kidding? I fought so hard
for these guys to put her back in.
- She kicks butt.
- You did, actually, that's true.
I don't deal in chance.
- You little wench.
- This is my favourite scene.
"Fuck it."
Fuck it.
I cursed.
Yoghurt?
This is so not fair that Eric's
not here to defend himself.
'Cause he is going to listen
to this and hate us.
This is so genius.
He is going to do...
Eric's going to do his own commentary.
Love Michelle's expression here.
Wait, the little eyebrow thing
she does is genius.
No, no. Watch, it's coming.
Yeah.
- There it is.
- That's good. I noticed that as well.
Yeah, that's a little bit of acting there.
Well done.
All right, here we go, here we go.
"You're gonna have to kill me."
"We all die down here."
Yoghurt.
And here we go.
Yes, that was beautiful.
By the way, we had him to work off of.
The puppet was actually there,
so we weren't working with nothing.
Were we? It's part of...
No, most of it you were
working with nothing.
No, no, no, when we were with B camera,
we didn't.
Well, I was. I didn't.
You worked with the actual monster.
- This is great.
- I think we were following a beam of light.
- Somebody had a flash light.
- That's right.
Yeah. Because all the shots
of the creature were done
separate to the shots of the actors,
- because it's a complete reverse.
- What do you do in this situation?
But that scene where I, like, flew back,
I was actually flying back from the puppet.
That is so cool.
- I'm sorry.
- Yeah.
I mean, you just don't get situations
like that in your typical sort of
- horror flick.
- Day to day life.
Wait. Speak for yourself, right?
So, we're meant to think
that the creature's there.
You know the creature is not gonna open
a door like that, man.
No. But you've seen when the power's
been cut before, doors open automatically.
- Yeah. That's what we tried to create.
- Whatever.
But if it doesn't work, you speak to Paul.
And look, I'm ready to handle the axe.
I'm like, "Yeah. Come."
- What the fuck?
- What the fuck was that?
What the fuck was that?
What the fuck?
In the scene coming up, this scene here,
this has got one of my favourite
features from the game,
which is the zombies that crawl along
the floor and try to eat your feet.
- But what happened?
- The crawling ones.
And also, Milla, she'll probably tell us
about what happened in this scene.
- This was so horrendous.
- Where...
- This was the worst...
- You hit him real bad, didn't you?
- You hit him hard.
- I did not hit him hard.
You hit everybody hard.
What are you talking about?
Okay. Listen.
First of all, I did not hit him hard.
It was a plastic axe.
- It was a very hard plastic axe, if I recall.
- It hurt him.
- I was playing with that thing. It was hard.
- I had calls from his agent.
Yeah, I'm sure you did, because all these
male actors are such pussies.
I had calls from your agent
as well, on occasion.
You're kidding me. He got...
Yeah, I remember.
He was kind of pissed off that day.
He screamed at me so loud.
Because it is kind of fucked up, Milla.
I mean, come on.
You know what?
We're making a movie like this,
- accidents happen, okay?
- Let me guess, you got into the role.
I'd like to see him trying to do
this whole thing in a miniskirt, okay?
- I wouldn't like to see that.
- She was PMSing that day, James.
- Yeah!
- Fucker.
- That's right. Hurt. Hurt. Hurt. Asshole.
- Was that when she really hit him?
Yes, if we let that shot go on
for another second,
you'd see that she nailed him there with...
- Right in the head.
- But you know what? He got so pissed at me
and I'm sorry, it was an accident, people.
Shit happens, man.
It's not like I wanted to do that.
I should have, for all the shit he gave me.
Well, that part...
You guys can cut that, right?
Needle's in.
- Now, this looks like I'm totally sticking you.
- By the way, you were totally sticking me.
Because my hair was all wet,
and you were all Vaselined.
I had, like, five really big bumps
on my arm from...
- Look. Okay, Michelle. Now we all know...
- Thinking that she was injecting you...
...that Michelle is gonna complain
about the little scratches.
I'm complaining now.
- Because she's led a very sheltered life.
- Yes. I was very hurt, you know.
I'm really delicate.
- I'm a fragile girl.
- Blood by L'Oréal, on her neck.
Was it, really?
- Because you're worth it, Michelle.
- Oh, yes.
But you were so damn greasy,
I couldn't get that needle in your arm.
Oh, you know.
- They said she has to be greasy.
- It wasn't like the night before,
you know, when it was just easy.
- It's like, one, two, three.
- Yeah, grease me up.
They'd put the pomade on my head
and everything.
- Oh, shit. That's for sure gonna get cut.
- I was like, "Listen, man,
"you guys are bugging."
It's good, this bit.
Look. I actually look like I like you.
- I mean, I look like I'm gonna miss you.
- Were you crying?
- Now, that's acting.
- Were you really crying?
Is she alive? She's still alive? No. No.
This is where I wish that I, like,
could inject myself and become a zombie
and have, like, half of my brain working.
Just try to rip my neck off.
I'm fine, guys.
It's just that my face is dismembered,
and I have pus in my eyeballs, but...
I'm really fine. Can I borrow your gun?
- I'm gonna shoot you before I eat you.
- This is totally normal.
- I look like a zombie.
- Michelle is doing the eye thing.
- She's doing... She's working those eyes.
- That's Paul, man.
- He keeps telling me to work the eyes.
- Do the eye thing.
- That was my main direction.
Do the eye thing. Do the eye thing more.
Yeah. That was his main direction
to Michelle is, "Do the eye thing,"
and to me, "Don't ever do that again.
I hate it."
It was, like, his best direction.
You didn't like that piece of direction?
- I thought it was very direct.
- I listened.
- That's why it's called direction.
- Direct direction.
You're a direct director.
- "Get us the fuck out of here."
- He cursed.
- They can do that in an R-rated movie.
- No.
But he looks like
a wholesome American boy.
Oh, no.
Now, how come nobody sees him
get splattered against anything?
- Was that the budget? Was that the budget?
- The train...
We couldn't afford it.
And also we might wanna bring him back
for the sequel.
He's still crawling around.
- Really?
- He's crawling around down there.
- Yeah. I love this sequence.
- This is awesome.
- That was a CGI bullet.
- Nice.
That's KY jelly, that nasty stuff.
How was that? What did they do?
Was that a CG tongue or was that...
Yeah. That was an animatronic creature
- and the CG tongue.
- I mean, that's just my acting, Michelle.
- I mean, like, I am selling it.
- Animatronics.
It was quite handy
those pipes were there, wasn't it?
- And the funniest thing is I almost...
- That was classic.
...died in that pipe shot
because I just wanted to make it look so real
and in reality, like, why?
Milla, the pipes weren't made of
real metal, were they?
- Yeah. They were made of cardboard.
- They were made of...
- And Michelle...
- How could you die out there?
There's half in cardboard
and half that were real
to give you that weighty feeling.
Now, this scene here...
See, I fought so hard for this shot
to stay in the movie, Michelle.
Because I just thought, literally,
she looks more feminine
as a zombie waking up
than in the whole movie.
Apart from that... No, no, no. Apart from that
really super cute shot in the beginning
where she's like... Scary.
No, no, no. Listen, that's all because
I refused to wear the tights.
I refused to wear the spandex tights
because I look like the Tomb Raider chick.
And I was like, "That movie already..."
No, but, you guys...
You have to, like, go back to that shot
and just sort of play it in slow motion
like that little neck and her little head,
like a little bird waking up.
No. Honestly,
I just thought it was so gorgeous.
- You're sick, Milla.
- I know I'm sick...
- But honestly, it was so pretty.
- You're demented.
That must have smelled.
You gotta remember that feeling
for Tina Modotti.
Totally.
- But, like, without the makeup.
- Without the zombie stuff.
After the etiquette lessons.
That... You guys didn't make faces
like it stunk.
That must have stunk.
- That must have smelled really, really bad.
- The tongue?
Well, just the creature being burnt alive.
Humans being burnt...
I've passed by crematoriums
and it really smells bad.
It stinks. You look like you smelt a fart.
- Well, they're already dead in crematoriums.
- It's pretty grim.
They're not burnt alive.
No. No, no, no. You know what I mean?
- Where they cremate people?
- I hope not.
That's what I meant.
What I meant is where they cremate people.
I thought, cremate, crematorium.
- No, that's where they make cream.
- Oh, they make cream there? Really?
That's what you smelt. Cream.
I don't know.
I never did research on it, you know.
Dead people being burnt alive
and what it's called and where they do it.
- That's where they made cream.
- Never really cared much for dead people.
Look at... Look at this shadow.
This is a genius bit of producing
because we couldn't afford
- to build a really big door.
- Which I don't get this.
So we just had a shadow of a big door.
I don't get this at all, though.
Where is that door?
It's behind the camera.
- It's casting a shadow onto the staircase.
- No. But, I mean...
- The door that Michelle...
- Yeah. It looks like it was part of the big...
You guys... Doesn't anybody see?
Like, Michelle opened that door
with a fire-thrower or whatever.
- That door was broken.
- It's a different door.
Yeah. That's different.
- It's completely different.
- We had two doors in the budget.
This is great.
This is when Eric's arm starts hurting.
Something really unpleasant
is about to happen.
Also, if you're looking for continuity flaws,
in the shot,
the crane shot beforehand where
you're walking across the dining room,
Milla isn't carrying the nice, beautiful box
that cost us a fortune.
- She's actually carrying a cardboard box...
- Because we didn't have it.
...wrapped in, like, baker foil, tin foil.
And we had to get that shot at, like,
6:00 in the morning
because the sun was coming up
and we didn't...
The prop guy had accidentally
locked the box in the studio.
Yeah. That was another great moment.
The great thing about these scenes is
that Eric had such muscular control
that he actually did a lot of the work on
his arm himself. He didn't even have to CG.
Yeah. Some of it looks like
a visual effects shot,
the way his skin is rippling,
but that's just him.
But that's just his muscles rippling.
There's actually only one
visual effects shot in this,
which is when the worm starts
coming out of his arm.
And that, by the way... And now
you're gonna see Jeremy one more time.
- She's a bit...
- And there...
Jeremy is down, and that was it for the day.
Did you just see that, you guys?
That was Eric. That wasn't CG.
- Okay, now it's CG.
- That's not Eric.
No. That's Eric.
Good Lord, Eric, that's a remarkable talent
you have.
You actually hit Jeremy so hard
he had to leave the set after this.
That's what I said.
End of the day for Jeremy.
You guys called this project Nemesis.
So, that means that
Eric's gonna be Nemesis?
- Maybe.
- Hell, yeah.
- What do you mean, maybe?
- You got worms coming out of his arms.
- Of course he'll be Nemesis.
- And they said they're using him for the...
- Nemesis project.
Depends how the renegotiation
with his agent goes.
- Well, whatever.
- That's why he's got his own commentary.
The fact is... I mean, if he doesn't...
I mean, come on.
You think Eric's not gonna want to be
in the next movie?
- He's gonna do it.
- Of course he will.
And if he doesn't, you could just have him
already so mutated that...
He could be anybody.
- Well, yeah. That's just it.
- Now, here comes...
- He could be anybody, he's so mutated.
- ...Jason Isaac's voiceover again.
- Unpaid and uncredited.
- Jason, who has been in all of our films.
Yeah. He's also the bad guy in The Patriot.
Poor Chris. You cut out his shot.
This is the infamous eye shot
- that you'll see in the video game.
- My production partner, actually,
was one of the uncredited doctors here,
but unfortunately, his shot was cut.
It's all right, Chris.
No, it's there, Milla.
- Well, yeah. It's very faint.
- In and out of the eyeball. That's cool.
- This was...
- That was my great hair dressing.
- Who designed the dress?
- Me.
Because that's just impeccable work
right there.
- I designed the dress, I designed my hair.
- You designed the dress yourself?
- Yeah.
- It's great.
- Milla was really creative.
- Chris, Milla's production partner
- almost had a fit.
- That looks like Paul's haircut
towards the end of the movie.
I wonder how he got that.
That Mohawk.
- What happened?
- Twat shot.
- Nice.
- What's up with that, Milla?
You're complaining about me
and my leather bra at the Kit Kat Club.
Look at you.
- That's gonna be popular on DVD.
- I know. I know. I'm not complaining.
Are you kidding? I'd love to see you
in your leather bra at the Kit Kat Club.
- Me and my leather bra.
- You and everybody else. Jesus Christ.
So you decided to do the haircut
with the two dots or was that Paul?
Well, no. I mean, we sort of talked about
what my hair should be like and...
- I like that. That retro punk look.
- Yeah.
I mean, we were like,
it has to be something...
- Funky.
- It's very, very cool.
How did your hair grow back after that?
Are you kidding? It's not even grown back.
No way. Oh, my God.
You're a sick puppy. You're dedicated, man.
I was almost in the film again,
just coming up.
Wait. Look.
- Sometimes it's funny, just...
- But I couldn't do that.
- It just pops out like that.
- It was too much acting...
- I tried to do that and I wasn't good at...
- So got one of the prop guys...
This, this... This, I find it amazing.
- That you can... Yeah. Totally.
- How quickly...
- This is like... You're a security expert.
- Because she's a security expert.
And I didn't know that with a pin,
you just swipe a pin and then that's it, man.
- Are you kidding?
- Go to an ATM,
you do this, money pours out.
- No, she's not just swiping it. Look.
- Yeah, it's the push.
She's now pushing it in the right area, see.
- It's all about trajectory.
- It's all about...
Listen, don't ask me. I'm just the actor here.
I said it's not believable. Please.
Like, how many kids now
are gonna walk around with pins.
Please. No.
- It does not work.
- That's that infamous...
- ...Resident Evil lock pick, though.
You're gonna need that later to open
the door that's gonna get you out of here.
- Right. You never actually see it.
- That's true.
It's all about the lock pick.
That was the lock pick idea. Wasn't it, Paul?
- Yeah, damn straight.
- It's great.
I wish that in the video game
you could, you know,
open car doors with your lock pick,
but you can't in the video game.
But you can in the movie. That's great.
This is a prequel.
That's what happens in prequels.
Thank you.
Thank you, Michelle, for that rant.
That was the video game geek in me
coming out.
This was shot in downtown Toronto.
This is my favourite shot of
the whole movie, by the way. This is...
There's a great ad for Umbrella
on the side of that bus.
It says, "Umbrella medical,
making teddy that little bit softer."
It looks like a kid
sleeping with a teddy bear.
And there's Jeremy
on the front page of the newspaper again.
How did you guys
get that newspaper printed?
You just have your prop people do it?
So if we can make something like the liquor,
I think we can pull that off.
They had people on the scene
right there to capture it.
No. What I'm saying, like, did you go
to the newspaper company?
If we can do this shot,
if we can decimate an entire city...
This is sick.
What was the budget again
by the end of the film?
By the end of the film? Nothing.
Because we'd spent it all.
No. But I'm saying, by the end of the film,
what had you spent?
On like, just as far as just making the film?
- Not enough for my taste.
- Production. Not post.
- They should have paid us all a lot more.
- Probably, probably...
- ...million.
- Yeah.
- Come on.
- Really? That much?
Wait. A million over budget.
- I don't know. No...
- No, we did not go over budget.
And on that note...
- So you guys did this...
- Absolutely no over budget.
You did this whole masterpiece off of
like 30 mil, around that area?
- A little more.
- Forty?
No. Not 40.
- See, this song is so cool.
- Well, this is Slipknot.
This is really... I really like this song.
Oh, we've missed our names, Paul.
That would have been cool, Paul,
if you were a zombie in one of the scenes.
- Alex Berner, our brilliant film editor.
- I would like to have been.
- I just... I never had time.
- Yeah. No doubt.
You know, to like turn up two hours early
to go into makeup.
Then I just wouldn't have slept at all.
He'll be that zombie that's pointing
his fingers around.
So our production designer,
also, was our costume designer,
- which we haven't done before.
- My armpits are kicking.
- They are quite bad...
- I tried to blame it on the dog,
but then I was like, "Damn..."
Yeah. It wasn't my dog's poopie that smelt.
No. My armpits don't smell like poop,
they're just musky.
Is that what they call it these days?
So, Paul, what does the "W" and the "S"
stand for, Paul?
W.S.
- So that's not...
- Samuel Williams...
- Wolf Sutcliffe.
Wolf Sutcliffe.
- What is that? What does it stand for?
- I'm not telling you.
- Come on, man.
- Come on. Guess.
William sucks.
Said... Sam...
- Sam. You've said that like five times.
- They weren't sure
- if you were a boy or a...
- So obviously, it's not Sam, okay?
So they said it's William Sally?
There's a really good bit coming up
where we change track and then we...
Paul cleverly takes one of Michelle's lines
and puts it into the track.
You're kidding me.
I never stay for the credits.
- Well, that's why we did it.
- That should be interesting.
Because I figure if you stick around
for all of these credits,
you deserve something extra.
No, no, no. We gotta watch it now,
because neither of us are gonna
stick around at the premiere for the credits.
- That's for sure.
- You'll be whisked away to some penthouse.
- Yeah, right.
- Yeah. I wish.
All of you must die.
You are all going to die down here.
- They were a really great German crew.
- Her voice wasn't that puny, was it?
- No. Her voice is so awesome. I love her.
- Very, very good.
- Die Nefzers. Brilliant special effects team.
- Just brilliant.
Disabling will result
in loss of primary power.
Those German stuntmen were really
tough as well. These guys...
I never had stuntmen stand
so close to explosions. Yeah.
They should be burnt, over and over again.
- They were real tough.
- Heads smacking the floor.
- Special Photography, Jany Thomas.
- I know.
They were almost as tough as the two of us.
It's crazy.
"I don't mind if you punch me in the face.
It is okay. You are a girl. I can take it."
That sounded Dutch, actually.
I'm bad. I don't mind.
You liked punching people,
you've punched a few people over there.
Oh, God. Yeah. But I never came in contact
with their faces, as Milla did.
She was the one who actually hit people.
I know how to, you know,
kind of just steer clear of
- actually harming people.
- Yeah. That's the thing.
It's like, you don't ask me to play fight,
I don't see the difference.
When I shoot my fist out, it hits its mark.
- Okay. That's just what happens.
- Yeah, man.
Especially if it's the director.
I don't know how to, like, stop
an inch away from people's faces.
She hit you twice, didn't she, man?
She copped you twice, or was it just once?
It's just... That one you could see.
Yeah. Milla's a feisty girl.
The rest are all with my foot in his ass.
Just you wait till the sequel.
- I will have my revenge.
- I just heard the sound effects.
- Hang on.
- Is this it?
- No. Coming up.
- No. It's...
It's hours away. We're gonna be
sitting here for another 15 minutes.
This is Coldchamber, right?
- Yeah.
- Coltrane?
- Coldchamber.
- Who are these people?
No. We couldn't afford Coltrane.
No, it's Coldchamber.
Oh, there goes the credit for...
We didn't think Coltrane would have
been appropriate somehow.
I love these guys.
What the fuck is that?
- That's why they chose heavy metal.
- It's really hard to do that.
Because it sounds like...
- Did they do an acoustic version of this?
- It's really hard
to do that at a concert and, like,
still have your voice afterwards.
- Oh, Jeremy went to a Slipknot concert.
- Look, look, look.
Paul, here it is. Listen, listen.
- This is a track by Fear Factory.
- Where's the Celine Dion track?
- Couldn't afford it.
- Who wants to afford it?
- I think it's on Blade.
- Are you kidding?
- No.
- Fuck off.
Listen. Don't start talking shit, Jeremy,
because we...
Now, listen, listen, listen.
Milla, Milla. Listen.
- It's coming up.
- Sometimes I feel...
- What is this?
- Listen, listen, listen...
Why did you do that for?
Who the hell is gonna sit through
all of that, anyway?
Well, that band will. I can tell you.
I wanted to alter the last credit
here to this movie...
You know, it says in the end,
"This movie has no..." What is it?
No... "It doesn't resemble people
living or dead."
And I wanted to go, "Living or undead."
But I wasn't allowed to.
Because they said we might get sued.
- You're kidding me. That's pathetic.
- By the undead.
By some dork.
I just didn't let him do it.
- I just...
- It's a beautiful film.
- Bye-bye. Bye-bye, everyone.
- Yeah, man.
- Screen Gems, we love you.
- So, this is Jeremy, saying goodbye.
This is Michelle Rodriguez saying goodbye.
This is Milla Jovovich.